<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-08-25T17:04:09+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">cjtb</title><subtitle>this is my main node on the internet
</subtitle><author><name>Clare Birch</name></author><entry><title type="html">Unlearning Perfectionism</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/unlearning-perfectionism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Unlearning Perfectionism" /><published>2022-04-02T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2022-04-02T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/unlearning-perfectionism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/unlearning-perfectionism.html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been mulling over Arun Prasad’s ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://arunkprasad.com/log/unlearning-perfectionism/&quot;&gt;Unlearning Perfectionism&lt;/a&gt;’ for the past couple of months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was introduced to me on a semi-drunken night out at Quantum Australia during a conversation about PhDs and finding your life’s work. The person I spoke with was, himself, Christian. I had forgotten that the deeper-thinking apologeticists are also astute observers of humanity. Such people often have the uncanny ability to cut through you with honesty and kindness—a rarity I admire immensely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He thought I would benefit from Unlearning Perfectionism (am I so transparent?). After two sentences I was quite rapt. Pained and relieved at once. Perhaps most current to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Perfectionism endures because it has its merits, and we must see these clearly as well. It establishes a high standard and feeds on a source of intense energy, i.e. the fear of losing our identity and self-worth. So it is no surprise that some of the world’s luminaries have made contracts with it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sans the navel gazing you might expect here, I will say I am focusing on excellence rather than perfection currently, with some structure along the lines of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One alternative with a similar flavor is excellence, which differs in two respects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Where perfectionism focuses on achieving, excellence focuses on pursuing. Success and failure aren’t ever in our full control. All we can control is what we choose to do right now, in this moment. Our attention shifts from outcomes to process.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Where perfectionism focuses on fixed outcomes, excellence focuses on better outcomes. Any real situation can always be improved. Since there is no perfect outcome, perfection is impossible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Process over outcomes; systems over goals; growth mindset over fixed mindset; satisficing over maximizing; professionalism over amateurism; boring fundamentals over flashy tricks; response over reaction; agency over passivity; presence over regret and worry. No matter what you call it, the distinction is the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am an Associate Venture Capitalist. This is a title that, if you knew me two years ago, would make you laugh. It is, ironically, a journey of &lt;em&gt;slow&lt;/em&gt;, deep learning in a fast environment that I am generally enjoying—-with caveats and battles, of course, as you always find in situations of love. It is not a journey that survives under the stifling gables of perfectionism. At the end, I am loving seeing this version of myself emerge.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Clare Birch</name></author><category term="oldblog yawyr" /><summary type="html">I’ve been mulling over Arun Prasad’s ‘Unlearning Perfectionism’ for the past couple of months.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You Are What You Read 5</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Are What You Read 5" /><published>2020-01-06T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2020-01-06T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-5.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fill your brain with good today. As I empty my time of social media (difficult), I try to fill it again with challenging, enjoyable Good (this has mostly meant Buffy the Vampire Slayer, but we’re getting there). Here are some (non-Buffy) things that have stood out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/f/1uwnhtyoqo?utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=p_na+share-sheet&amp;amp;rcid=3380a204ac5b4d4bb261d7ca881c770d&quot;&gt;Donate to Deadly Science’s bushfire appeal&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We’re helping fire-affected schools with resourcing, which is a mighty task. Also, donate to the RFS.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wnycstudios.org/podcasts/anthropocene-reviewed/episodes/anthropocene-reviewed-auld-lang-syne&quot;&gt;The Anthropocene Reviewed: Auld Lang Syne&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;John Green reviews an aspect of this strange human experience of ours: Auld Lang Syne, my preferred holiday song. Reflecting on his friendship with author Amy Krouse Rosenthal, who passed away in 2017, Green remarks, “…we are here. Meaning that we are together, and not alone…that we are, that we exist…that we are here, that a series of astonishing unlikelihoods has made us possible, and here possible. We might never know why we are here, but we can still proclaim in hope that we are here. I don’t think such hope is foolish or idealistic or misguided. I believe that hope is, for lack of a better word, true. We live in hope that life will get better and, more importantly, that it will go on. That love will survive, even though we will not. As Emily Dickinson put it, ‘Hope is the thing with feathers / that perches in the soul / and sings the tune without the words / and never stops at all.’” It is the kind of controlled meandering we have come to expect from Green. It is lovely and heartbreaking and hopeful.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com.au/House-Spirits-Isabel-Allende/dp/1501117017&quot;&gt;The House of the Spirits&lt;/a&gt; by Isabel Allende
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I love a family epic. This is, by all measures, a gorgeous novel. It is not One Hundred Years of Solitude, though I understand why one might compare the two. It is about women. You should read it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theatlantic.com/technology/archive/2020/01/how-death-itunes-explains-2010s/604291/&quot;&gt;How the Death of iTunes Explains the 2010s&lt;/a&gt; by Robinson Meyer in The Atlantic
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I think the title speaks for itself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2017/03/pressure-doesnt-have-to-turn-into-stress?utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_campaign=hbr&quot;&gt;Pressure Doesn’t Have to Turn Into Stress&lt;/a&gt; by Nicholas Petrie in the Harvard Business Review
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A useful reminder for the beginning of a new year. Wake up. Control your attention. Put things into perspective. Let go.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Clare Birch</name></author><category term="oldblog yawyr" /><summary type="html">FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Faculty Of Science Address</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/faculty-of-science-address.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Faculty Of Science Address" /><published>2019-08-08T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-08-08T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Faculty-of-Science-Address</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/faculty-of-science-address.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://clarejoy.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/c0c3982-r1-06-6.jpg?w=1568&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://clarejoy.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/c0c3982-r1-06-6.jpg?w=1568&quot; alt=&quot;A close shot of jacarandas in front of a sandstone building at the University of Sydney, on film&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently had the honour of giving the Address of the Faculty Scholar at our annual Faculty of Science awards night. I’ll admit I was petrified for days (weeks, even) leading up to the event, unsure of what message I thought was most important to get across. I settled on the below. Enjoy. Don’t judge (too hard).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good evening Dean, academic and professional staff, guests, and most importantly, students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want to talk to you about tonight is strictly speaking not on science. It’s rather about making science better, about stories and diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, I entered Sydney University with no intention of studying science, a head filled with visions of Robin Williams in Dead Poets Society, and the deepest conviction that I was going to become a desk-stomping, poetry-reciting English teacher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A child of the foster system, I know from a great deal of personal experience the power of strong mentorship and stability. I have been lucky to have these in brilliant foster parents and teachers throughout most of my life. My motivation was simple: I was going to change the world by changing worlds, just as mine had been.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was wrong. This became very clear to me when, at a welcome afternoon tea a little way in, I found myself complaining about my degree in exquisite detail to a lovely blonde lady who seemed altogether too interested in my input. A few minutes later, she introduced herself to the group as none other than our esteemed Chancellor, Belinda Hutchinson, and I promptly decided to change my course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve changed degrees twice, overall, and majors uncountably many times. I’ve dabbled in English and neuroscience and Arabic, and always come home to chemistry. I’m not telling you all this so that I come across as delightfully capricious or approachable or comfortably abject. The fact is that I am not yet very old, though I certainly feel it sometimes, and I am frankly not sure I have much to offer you by way of sage wisdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I have are stories like this, and some that are a little more serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But stories have been more than enough for me in mentoring and leadership. See, stories have the most remarkable, sometimes dangerous, power of taking on their own lives while also shaping the world around us. Fiction is an amazing thing, but as scientists we have an incredible tool in our individual stories to encourage genuine change in our fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your own narrative is a path carved through your own experience; it contains an abundance of data on what to do, what not to do, how to do it. This is why it’s important that I tell you tonight that I was fostered: in the UK, while 50% of the general population will make it to university, only 6% of people with experience in care will. I would not have made it here without incredible mentors and support and, importantly, a brother who part-carved the path before me. His story, always a step ahead of but similar to mine, brought the possibility of university to life for me: he was the only other person I knew with a similar background who had taken this step. In many ways, his story made mine possible. When you can look ahead and see someone, seeing yourself in the 6% becomes more conceivable. Their path makes yours clearer, realer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As science-doers, we can be hesitant to tell our individual stories: our work must stand on its own, we are often terrified of showing weakness or admitting failure, we are deeply concerned with fitting in and keeping up in a field mired in tradition but changing increasingly rapidly. This is important now more than ever: not only can our stories pave the way for greater diversity, they can help to rebuild trust in the public eye. We have a moral imperative to tackle the groundswell of anti-intellectualism that is wreaking havoc on our climate and our health. Being emphatically diverse encourages trust and empathy. It’s not a nicety, it’s a necessity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is it: students, you are in the process of writing a story that will change lives. Science needs your stories: your cultures, your genders, your sexualities, your cognitive differences, your opinions, your activism, your hobbies, your arts. It needs your experiences with mental health, with perfectionism, with failure. There is more, of course: bureaucracy and ingrained, often very physical, inaccessibility that needs to be rebuilt from the ground up. But your voice will change the culture and structures that hold others back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to leave you with the quote that made me decide to pursue science. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/We-Are-All-Stardust-Scientists-ebook/dp/B00BBF8FLO/ref=sr_1_1?crid=34TNTQV3Q0LHQ&amp;amp;dib=eyJ2IjoiMSJ9.9d665duWc-GDw0Qg44APi3dqkwVY7SAD7MlvAoPwOFVP0CK-StiHEu3g8ADZcAJ0L3gnssvYgbSAFKzTtXan1x4Y4dg-ueH1PO_v72jf-SdQYhPWrk1j_8HsmYeIywaXzlHF13TRaS7fELCtgFrrpIOE3v1nAUWK3JfEYUSdZu5-9x2-FI5Y5Iva0ZEXnVi3hChJYMXxKsMDUOzS4wsrLek7j9KMkAEEoCKz4tfLMag.JSY-MIzrn2WgU2Nf8Q7CxC3Jd9XIkCyHgDTXgg_ZNv4&amp;amp;dib_tag=se&amp;amp;keywords=we+are+all+stardust&amp;amp;qid=1724548470&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;sprefix=we+are+all+stardu%2Cstripbooks-intl-ship%2C372&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot;&gt;An interviewer asks Roald Hoffmann&lt;/a&gt;–my personal favourite chemist, if that’s a normal thing to have-—what makes him so “unusually successful” (in my opinion, this is a fairly reasonable description of a Nobel Prize winner). Hoffmann says this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Maybe a better ability to empathise with other people. I’ve always had a good sense of what difficulties my colleagues in the lab are facing—even if they haven’t verbalised them. And I’ve then solved those particular problems.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So students, do your best science. Continue to be exceptional. And while you do, remember that empathy can empower the human spirit just as much as discovery. Remember that science needs you, needs your stories. Remember to speak up. You never know who might hear. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve added a link here to the collection of interviews from which the cited one came. It’s a genuinely life-changing read. I highly recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Clare Birch</name></author><category term="oldblog" /><summary type="html">FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Giving This International Women’s Day</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/giving-this-international-women-s-day.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Giving This International Women’s Day" /><published>2019-03-08T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-03-08T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Giving-this-International-Women&apos;s-Day</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/giving-this-international-women-s-day.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy International Women’s Day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is a great chance to celebrate the women in your life – your mentors, mothers, inspirations, friends, colleagues, sisters, strangers…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also an opportunity to acknowledge that the difficulties that come with womanhood are vastly varied across the planet, and that as women in the Global North we have the ability to enact real, effective, positive change in the lives of women across the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an individual, you can do more than you realise. I’ve compiled a list of places to which you might like to consider contributing today. You obviously don’t have to – it’s just something I hope you’ll think about. There are plenty of other worthwhile causes, of course; these are just a few that I know and support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.givedirectly.org/&quot;&gt;Give directly&lt;/a&gt; to a woman in extreme poverty in Kenya or Uganda, so she can support her family as she thinks best. GiveDirectly is an initiative backed by GiveWell, Google, and pretty decent evidence.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support &lt;a href=&quot;https://learningpartnership.org/&quot;&gt;Women’s Learning Partnership&lt;/a&gt;, a UN-approved partnership of 20 autonomous organisations that promote women’s leadership and human rights in the Global South.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Donate to, or volunteer at, &lt;a href=&quot;https://sanctuaryhousing.org.au/&quot;&gt;one of Sydney’s many domestic violence shelters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An obstetric fistula is an injury that can occur in childbirth. It’s no longer an issue, for the most part, in developed countries, but due to poverty-related stunting and a lack of medical care, it’s still a huge problem in sub-Saharan Africa. Donations to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fistulafoundation.org/&quot;&gt;The Fistula Foundation&lt;/a&gt; can provide access to a life-changing surgery to reverse the effects of fistula.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.a21.org/&quot;&gt;The A21 Foundation&lt;/a&gt; works to eliminate sexual trafficking and slavery, and are always in need of support. It’s run by Christine Caine, whose passion for the cause is truly infectious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find more information about high-impact giving at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thelifeyoucansave.org/&quot;&gt;The Life You Can Save&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.givewell.org/&quot;&gt;GiveWell&lt;/a&gt;, among others.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Clare Birch</name></author><category term="oldblog" /><summary type="html">FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You Are What You Read 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Are What You Read 4" /><published>2017-11-19T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2017-11-19T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-4.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://clarejoy.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/c0c3982-r1-06-6.jpg?w=1568&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://clarejoy.wordpress.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/c0c3982-r1-06-6.jpg?w=1568&quot; alt=&quot;A close shot of jacarandas in front of a sandstone building at the University of Sydney, on film&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of a wedding (congrats Em and Euon!) and the general temporal disorientation brought about by exam season, this is like 24 hours late. These articles and videos have been a welcome relief; new information is the closest I’m getting to swanning around a different country, at least for now. So please, enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aljazeera.com/news/2017/11/chinua-achebe-google-honours-today-171116065724595.html&quot;&gt;Chinua Achebe: Why Google Honours Him Today&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I first came across Chinua Achebe in a Lit Theory class last year. ‘&lt;a href=&quot;https://polonistyka.amu.edu.pl/__data/assets/pdf_file/0007/259954/Chinua-Achebe,-An-Image-of-Africa.-Racism-in-Conrads-Heart-of-Darkness.pdf&quot;&gt;An Image of Africa: Racism in Conrad’s Heart of Darkness&lt;/a&gt;‘ was the first critical theory piece I enjoyed – Achebe’s writing is crisp and clear and engaging, carrying his passion and insight in a way that no other crit I’ve read has managed. This profile by Al Jazeera conveys all that and more.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rollingstone.com/glixel/features/neopets-a-look-into-early-2000s-girl-culture-w509885&quot;&gt;‘Neopets’: Inside Look at Early 2000s Internet Girl Culture&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This article is a banger. I love it. Excuse the grammatically incomplete title (An Inside Look?) and you’ll find a genuinely interesting piece that explores the role that Neopets (and other online RPGs like GaiaOnline, I’d say) played in developing a generation’s entrepreneurial and technical skills.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aljazeera.com/news/2017/11/happening-zimbabwe-171115054133319.html&quot;&gt;Zimbabwe: What’s Happening?&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Literally just what it says it is. Tensions have been escalating between Zimbabwe’s government (dictatorial, run by Pres Robert Mugabe) and its military since its Vice President was exiled last week. It’s still uncertain what’s going to happen, but news sites are calling it an “apparent coup.” You can also follow along on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/monkey-cage/wp/2017/11/15/heres-whats-happening-in-zimbabwe/?utm_term=.b92d239b0bc0&quot;&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/10/05/arts/how-do-you-say-email-in-yiddish.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;How Do You Say ‘Email’ in Yiddish?&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I’ve been watching The West Wing lately, and in Season 3 Toby and Bruno exchange the occasional remark peppered with Yiddish slang. Naturally, I’ve been looking up Yiddish. I came across this. It’s great.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vanityfair.com/news/2017/11/is-mark-zuckerberg-facebooks-last-true-believer&quot;&gt;Is Mark Zuckerberg Facebook’s Last True Believer?&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Good question. Read the article.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/11/10/style/modern-love-when-your-uber-driver-brings-a-time-machine.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;When Your Uber Driver Brings A Time Machine&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;What a title! This is a Modern Love piece that, for me, was a comfort. Underpinning its central coincidence is a gentle lesson in impermanence. Your life is long; many people will walk through it; you will learn a lot from them and, ultimately, it will be okay.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ba-CB6wVuvQ&amp;amp;ab_channel=LessonsfromtheScreenplay&quot;&gt;Whiplash vs. Black Swan – The Anatomy of the Obsessed Artist&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is one of the most viewed videos on this channel, so it’s not like it’s some rare find or anything, but cudos nonetheless to this guy for what is a fantastic deconstruction of this archetype. I am a big fan. He’s also done one on what makes Independence Day so great, which you should totally watch if we’re going to be mildly civil towards each other.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xw0GAInXkhA&quot;&gt;Art is Advertising for What We Really Need&lt;/a&gt;
Because I’m a sucker for The School of Life and this is such a lovely concept, that “it lies in the power of art to honour the elusive but real value of ordinary life.” Can you imagine being able to write like that? What a dream.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Clare Birch</name></author><category term="oldblog yawyr" /><summary type="html">FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You Are What You Read 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Are What You Read 3" /><published>2017-11-11T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2017-11-11T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-3.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2017/11/07/upshot/modern-love-what-we-write-when-we-write-about-love.html&quot;&gt;The Words Men and Women Use When They Write About Love&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Modern Love celebrated its 13th birthday this week, and they released a bunch of great pieces in celebration. This one was my favourite – a visual deconstruction of the words used in submissions, mapped across gender and success.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pudding.cool/2017/01/making-it-big/&quot;&gt;The Unlikely Odds of Making It Big&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A little pessimistic, but very interesting – this is another data piece, investigating the number of bands who move up from playing small shows. Works best on desktop.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/video/arts/100000005524840/the-louvre-abu-dhabi-lets-in-light-and-finally-the-public.html&quot;&gt;The Louvre Abu Dhabi Lets In Light and, Finally, The Public&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The New York Times does a daily “360” video, and this one is particularly great. Nothin’ much else to say tbh, I am in a mad rush.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sydneyreviewofbooks.com/what-we-talk-about-when-we-talk-about-australian-literature/&quot;&gt;What We Talk About When We Talk About Australian Literature&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Okay, hear me out. I know Austlit gets a bad wrap. I know. But it’s genuinely super interesting. I cleaned up my bookmarks bar this week and found this article from first year uni, so I’m sticking it here to inspire y’all to love Austlit.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cosmosmagazine.com/mathematics/the-numbers-are-in-ageing-is-inevitable&quot;&gt;The Numbers Are In: Ageing is Inevitable&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This one doesn’t have to be pessimistic if you embrace ageing. I’m keen to age. Fight me.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, the video that rocked my week: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dW4wpGg64pE&quot;&gt;Meryl Streep Meets Anna Wintour At Vogue&lt;/a&gt; (and they talk about women and Harvey Weinstein and journalism and truth in an age of ‘fake news’ and politics of distraction).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Clare Birch</name></author><category term="oldblog yawyr" /><summary type="html">FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You Are What You Read 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Are What You Read 2" /><published>2017-11-04T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2017-11-04T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-2.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cosmosmagazine.com/physics/einstein-bohr-and-the-origins-of-entanglement&quot;&gt;Einstein, Bohr, and the origins of entanglement&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Because we can all stand to learn some crazy physics, especially when it’s written so beautifully.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/27/style/modern-love-is-there-something-odd-about-being-single.html&quot;&gt;Is There Something Odd About Being Single?&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Because it’s relevant, and the NYTimes Modern Love column is amazing.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d3zTfXvYZ9s&amp;amp;ab_channel=minutephysics&quot;&gt;Time Travel in Fiction Rundown&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;MinutePhysics is a great channel, and this video (though not a minute long) is a fantastic representation of that.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bookdepository.com/This-is-How-You-Lose-Her/9780571294220&quot;&gt;This Is How You Lose Her by Junot Diaz&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cmsw.mit.edu/profile/junot-diaz/&quot;&gt;Diaz&lt;/a&gt; is a Dominican-America writer whose work carries the vastness of an entire culture somewhere between the lines. He also teaches at MIT – taking one of his classes is definitely a bucket list item!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pudding.cool/2017/10/satellites/&quot;&gt;Seeing Earth from Outer Space&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is a lovely little summary of the history of satellites, and a gorgeous (albeit glitchy) example of data journalism. Just make sure you scroll slowly. I found the Pudding on my hunt for some more content sources, and I have not been disappointed thus far.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pudding.cool/2017/05/song-repetition/&quot;&gt;Are Pop Lyrics Getting More Repetitive?&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This is another one from The Pudding, which I actually stole from my brother’s Facebook wall. Not even mad. It’s mathsy but also designy – I’m a big, big fan.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/09/12/obama-the-conservationist&quot;&gt;Obama The Conservationist&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Honestly, I used this as a source in an essay I wrote(/am still writing) this week. Nothing like a lil Obama love to make you feel better about the state of the world. A couple of notes: NOT “Obama, the Conversationalist” or “The Obama Conservationist” though these are also valid article ideas. Also totally gave up on the design for the story screen for this one.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And our bonus: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UaIZE6-yUKs&amp;amp;ab_channel=dodieVEVO&quot;&gt;Dodie’s “You” music video&lt;/a&gt;, shot entirely on Super8 in Paris by Bertie Gilbert, was a beautiful oasis in the middle of a crazy, assessment-ridden and emotionally frightening week. Also check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EaOS61kfblE&amp;amp;ab_channel=BertieGilbert&quot;&gt;Bertie’s break down of his process&lt;/a&gt;, which is just relaxing to watch, honestly.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Clare Birch</name></author><category term="oldblog yawyr" /><summary type="html">FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">You Are What You Read 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You Are What You Read 1" /><published>2017-10-27T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2017-10-27T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/you-are-what-you-read-1.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2017/10/25/world/africa/nigeria-boko-haram-suicide-bomb.html&quot;&gt;Boko Haram&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I’m not at all familiar with the situation in Nigeria, but this distressing, nuanced, thought-provoking article is a brilliant starting point. Its writer, Dionne Searcey, published a separate piece detailing the complexities she and the photographer, Adam Ferguson, had to navigate in its composition. Ferguson’s images had to conceal the girls’ identities while illuminating their stories, and he succeeds brilliantly.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/12/magazine/philip-pullman-returns-to-his-fantasy-world.html&quot;&gt;Philip Pullman&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A woman in my mother’s book club lent me Pullman’s His Dark Materials trilogy when I was about nine or ten, and I devoured them with an enthusiasm that I’m sure would have frightened many a churchgoer. This piece, illuminating Pullman in all his sharp honesty, brought me a special kind of joy. A good novel leaves us feeling as though we know the author as a dear friend, but all too often, we discover that the feeling is grossly misplaced. More often than not, as Foucault rudely pointed out, the author is not the writer – but in Pullman’s case, the character of his novels carries through precisely to him (though it would perhaps be more accurate to say that Pullman’s very essence is woven into his writing).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/24/opinion/collaborative-problem-solving-children.html?_r=0&quot;&gt;The Problem Child&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I love my work. I say it on the reg, and I’m pretty sure it’s insanely annoying that I do. I’m an educational assistant, and I truly wish that more people would engage with some of the stuff we deal with! It provides remarkable insight into human character and psychology/neurology, and often challenges us to be more empathetic and active in our daily interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aljazeera.com/indepth/opinion/talk-banning-funk-music-brazil-171015051721580.html&quot;&gt;Criminalising Funk Music&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;A genuinely interesting piece, detailing Brazil’s complex history with racism, as played out through its criminalisation of particular genres. (As a side note, Al-Jazeera is great. I’m a big fan).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aljazeera.com/indepth/opinion/muslim-feminism-driving-171002110808018.html&quot;&gt;Muslim Feminism&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It took me too long to come to understand that my (white, affluent) notion of ‘feminism’ was destructive; there is a far more important fight for women’s rights being played out, but western feminism seems blissfully ignorant of it. This article really drags your head out of the sand – again, I’m a big fan.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/10/05/opinion/sunday/nuclear-north-korea.html&quot;&gt;Inside North Korea&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I read this article a couple of weeks ago, and was completely entranced (or maybe paralysed). It is an honest, detailed, and expert view on a Times journalist’s recent trip to North Korea. I cannot recommend it enough.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aljazeera.com/indepth/opinion/locating-rohingya-time-space-170927100542729.html&quot;&gt;Locating the Rohingya&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For those of you who (like me) aren’t particularly caught up on the events in Myanmar, Al-Jazeera published this fantastic historical and sociological exposition of the Rohingya. It is illuminating. You’re welcome.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am super duper aware that all seven of these are only from two sources. They’re solid sources, but I’m still sorry – if I do this again, I’ll try to fix that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c5-LfK2i2J4&quot;&gt;And this video&lt;/a&gt;, from Alain de Botton’s The School of Life channel.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Clare Birch</name></author><category term="oldblog yawyr" /><summary type="html">FYI: This is an old post from an old blog I kept in uni</summary></entry></feed>